最专业冰火字幕
诚意奉献
专注GOT剧集
翻译 Saint HS
君临 King's Landing
翻译 蓝山脚下的林顿
翻译 兮迩CeCe
红堡
Red Keep
翻译 埃尔夫歪
奔流城Riverrun
校对 北落师门  依依Eva
校对 屈畅 赵琳
临冬城
Winterfell
后期 SerGawen@huiji.wiki
监制 北落师门
监制 临冬城的狮子
最专业的华语冰火资料站：        冰与火之歌中文维基
http://asoiaf.huiji.wiki
推广 baozhenyuawabi
绝境长城 the Wall
策划 衣柜军团
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
布拉佛斯
Braavos
联合出品
史诗图书 | 冰火中文维基 | 黑城堡奇幻微刊
Epic Books         ASOIAF.huiji.wiki        微信号：Heichengbao
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
衣柜字幕组
协力制作
史诗图书
Epic Books
ASOIAF.huiji.wiki
冰火中文维基
黑城堡
EPICASTLE
第九集
私生子之战
Battle of the Bastards
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
弥林的女王
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
不管看起来如何 我想你会发现这座城市是有起色的
Despite appearances, I think you'll find the city's on the rise.
我看我们还是找些掩护吧
Perhaps we should take shelter.
这座城市有起色？
The city's on the rise?
弥林非常坚强
Meereen is strong.
集市重开 商业恢复
Commerce has returned to the markets.
人民支持你
The people are behind you.
恩 当然 并不是所有人
Well, not all the people, of course.
没有一个统治者能得到所有人的支持
No ruler that ever lived had the support of all the people.
但这场战争的起因是弥林的重生
But the rebirth of Meereen is the cause of this violence.
奴隶主不会让弥林成功的
The Masters cannot let Meereen succeed.
但如果弥林成功的话 一个没有奴隶制
Because if Meereen succeeds, a city without slavery,
没有奴隶主的城市存在于世
a city without Masters...
会证明没人需要奴隶主
...it proves that no one needs a Master.
好
Good.
我们开始吧？
Shall we begin?
我们有什么计划吗？
Do we have a plan?
我会把奴隶主钉上十字架
I will crucify the Masters.
我会焚毁他们的舰队
I will set their fleets afire,
杀尽他们军队的每一个士兵
kill every last one of their soldiers,
把他们的城市夷为平地
and return their cities to the dirt.
这就是我的计划
That is my plan.
你不同意？
You don't approve?
你跟我说过 你知道你父亲是个怎样的人
You once told me you knew what your father was.
那你知道当兰尼斯特军队抵达君临城的时候
Did you know his plans for King's Landing
他的计划是什么吗？
when the Lannister armies were at his gates?
不知道吧
Probably not.
好吧 他告诉了我的哥哥 而詹姆告诉了我
Well, he told my brother and Jaime told me.
他在红堡下面藏了很多野火
He had caches of wildfire hidden under the Red Keep,
在公会大厅 在贝勒大圣堂
the Guildhalls, the Sept of Baelor,
以及所有的交通要道
all the major thoroughfares.
他想烧死城内他所有的臣民
He would have burned every one of his citizens.
忠臣和叛徒
The loyal ones and the traitors.
男人 女人和孩子
Every man, woman, and child.
所以詹姆杀了他
That's why Jaime killed him.
这是完全不同的
This is entirely different.
你说的是摧毁那些城市啊
You're talking about destroying cities.
所以并不是完全不同
It's not entirely different.
我想还有另一种办法
I'd like to suggest an alternate approach.
之前 我提议过和平解决
Once before, I offered you peace.
亚赞·佐·夸格兹
贤主
拉兹旦·莫·厄拉兹
贝里西奥·潘尼米恩
瓦兰提斯贵族
若你不是那么傲慢
If you had not been so arrogant,
你本可以带着一支舰队返回家乡
you could have returned to your homeland with a fleet of ships.
现在吗 你将徒步逃离奴隶湾
Instead, you will flee Slaver's Bay on foot
像一个真正的乞丐女王那样
like the beggar queen you are.
我们是来商谈投降条款的
We are here to discuss terms of surrender,
不是来互相辱骂的
not to trade insults.
条款很简单
The terms are simple.
你和你的异域朋友必须放弃大金字塔和弥林城
You and your foreign friends will abandon the Great Pyramid and the city of Meereen.
你从克拉兹尼·莫·纳克罗兹那儿偷来的无垢者
The Unsullied you stole from Kraznys mo Nakloz
会转售给价高者
will remain to be sold again to the highest bidder.
灰虫子
无垢者
你从克拉兹尼·莫·纳克罗兹那儿偷来的通译
The translator you stole from Kraznys mo Nakloz will remain
弥桑黛
也会转售给价高者
to be sold again to the highest bidder.
大金字塔下面的几头龙必须杀掉
The dragons beneath the Great Pyramid will be slaughtered.
看来我们没有表达清楚
We obviously didn't communicate clearly.
我们来这儿是来商讨你们的投降条款 而不是我的
We're here to discuss your surrender, not mine.
我知道 让自己适应现实
I imagine it's difficult
有些困难
adjusting to the new reality.
但你的统治已经完蛋了
Your reign is over.
我的统治才刚刚开始
My reign has just begun.
卓耿
丹妮的黑龙
雷哥/韦赛利昂
丹妮的绿龙/白龙
达里奥·纳哈里斯
雇佣兵
龙焰
Dracarys.
你们的人可以选择
为这些永远不会为你们而战的主人战死
还是回到家人的身边
感谢你们的舰队
Thank you for the armada.
女王陛下的确喜欢舰船
Our queen does love ships.
那么 我们上一次谈判的时候达成了一个协议
Now, last time we spoke, we made a pact.
但你们违反了这个协议
You violated that pact.
举兵攻打我们
You declared war upon us.
虽说女王陛下宽厚仁慈
Though our queen does have a forgiving nature,
但挑起战争是不能被原谅的
this cannot be forgiven.
女王陛下坚持要你们其中的一个人死
Our queen insists that one of you must die
以示惩戒
as punishment for your crimes.
别人的死看上去
It always seems a bit abstract, doesn't it,
总是无关紧要 是不是？
other people dying?
他 他应该死
Him. He should die.
对 他 他不是我们一伙的
Yes, him. He's not one of us.
他是外人 出身低下
He's an outsider, a lowborn.
他不为我们说话
He does not speak for us.
求你了
Please.
把这发生的事告诉你的人
Tell your people what happened here.
告诉他们你是因为女王陛下的仁慈才活下来
Tell them you live by the grace of Her Majesty.
他们要是想来寻仇
When they come forward with notions of retribution
或者想恢复奴隶城邦过去的荣耀时
or ideas about returning the slave cities to their former glory,
提醒他们
remind them what happened
在“风暴降生”丹妮莉丝和她的龙来到弥林之后都发生了什么
when Daenerys Stormborn and her dragons came to Meereen.
你不必来的
You don't have to be here.
不 我必须来
Yes, I do.
珊莎·史塔克
琼恩·雪诺
拉姆斯·波顿
我挚爱的妻子
My beloved wife.
我想死你了
I've missed you terribly.
谢谢你将波顿夫人安然无恙地送还
Thank you for returning Lady Bolton safely.
现在 下马然后跪在我面前
Now, dismount and kneel before me,
哈拉德·卡史塔克
卡霍城伯爵
交出军队 承认我是真正的临冬城公爵和北境守护
surrender your army and proclaim me the true Lord of Winterfell and Warden of the North.
我就赦免你背弃守夜人的罪
I will pardon you for deserting the Night's Watch.
也会赦免这些背叛我家族的领主们
I will pardon these treasonous lords for betraying my house.
莱安娜·莫尔蒙
熊岛伯爵夫人
按我说的做 杂种
Come, bastard,
你没有人手 没有马匹
you don't have the men, you don't have the horses,
你也没有临冬城
and you don't have Winterfell.
为什么要让这些可怜虫白白送死呢？
Why lead those poor souls into slaughter?
没必要打仗
There's no need for a battle.
下马 下跪
Get off your horse and kneel.
我很仁慈的
I'm a man of mercy.
你说得对
You're right.
没必要打仗
There's no need for a battle.
小琼恩·安柏
最后壁炉城伯爵
数以千计的人也不用死
Thousands of men don't need to die.
我们中的一个去死就可以
Only one of us.
让我们用古老的办法来解决
Let's end this the old way.
就你和我
You against me.
托蒙德
野人领袖
戴佛斯·席渥斯
洋葱骑士
我听了不少你的故事 杂种
I keep hearing stories about you, bastard.
北境人说起你时
The way people in the North talk about you,
总说你的剑术是有史以来最好的
you're the greatest swordsman who ever walked.
也许你确实有那么好
Maybe you are that good.
也许没有
Maybe not.
我不知道自己能否打败你
I don't know if I'd beat you.
但我知道我的军队会击败你的军队
But I know that my army will beat yours.
我有六千人
I have 6,000 men.
你有我的一半多吗？
You have, what, half that?
一半都没有？
Not even?
是啊 你人多
Aye, you have the numbers.
当你的人得知你不会为他们而战时
Will your men want to fight for you
他们是否还会为你而战呢？
when they hear you wouldn't fight for them?
他很厉害 非常厉害
He's good. Very good.
告诉我 你会眼睁睁看你弟弟死去
Tell me, will you let your little brother die
仅仅因为你太过骄傲不肯投降吗？
because you're too proud to surrender?
我们怎么知道他真在你手里？
How do we know you have him?
现在 如果你想救…
Now, if you want to save...
你明天就将受死 波顿大人
You're going to die tomorrow, Lord Bolton.
睡个好觉
Sleep well.
你妹妹是个不错的女人
She's a fine woman, your sister.
我很期待她回到我的枕边
I look forward to having her back in my bed.
你们也都是英俊的汉子
And you're all fine-looking men.
我的狗非常渴望见到你们
My dogs are desperate to meet you.
七天没给它们喂食了 它们饥饿难耐
I haven't fed them for seven days. They're ravenous.
不知道它们会先吃哪个部位呢
I wonder which parts they'll try first.
眼睛？
Your eyes?
蛋蛋？
Your balls?
很快便见分晓
We'll find out soon enough.
早上见吧 杂种
In the morning, then, bastard.
他要是聪明 就会待在
If he was smart, he'd stay inside
临冬城内等我们出动
the walls of Winterfell and wait us out.
这不是他的作风 他知道北境人都在观望
That's not his way. He knows the North is watching.
如果其他家族嗅到他的弱点
If the other houses sense weakness on his part,
他们便不再惧怕他
they'll stop fearing him.
他不能接受这个 恐惧是他的力量之源
He can't have that. Fear is his power.
这也是他的弱点 他的士兵不想为他而战
It's his weakness, too. His men don't want to fight for him.
他们被迫为他而战 若他们感到大势已去……
They're forced to fight for him. If they feel the tide turning...
我担心的不是他的士兵
It's not his men that worry me.
而是他的马
It's his horses.
我知道骑兵的能耐
I know what mounted knights can do to us.
你和史坦尼斯轻而易举击溃了我们 就像往雪地里撒尿
You and Stannis cut through us like piss through snow.
我们在侧翼挖好堑壕
We're digging trenches all along our flanks.
他们便不能通过两翼包围
They won't be able to hit us the way that Stannis hit you,
像史坦尼斯击溃你们一样击溃我们
in a double envelopment.
他们只能正面冲锋
A pincer move.
没办法从两翼攻击我们
They won't be able to hit us from the sides.
很好
Good.
关键是要引诱他们主动发起冲锋
It's crucial that we let them charge at us.
敌众我寡 我们需要耐心
They've got the numbers, we need the patience.
如果让他冲进我们的阵型中央 他会继续追击
If we let him buckle our center, he'll pursue.
届时我们便将他三面包围
Then we'll have him surrounded on three sides.
你真认为那娘们会和你们正大光明地打仗？
Did you really think that cunt would fight you man-to-man?
不
No.
但我想激怒他
But I wanted to make him angry.
我想让他朝我们全速扑来
I want him coming at us full tilt.
我们应该睡会儿
We should all get some sleep.
歇息吧 琼恩·雪诺 我们明天还需要你保持清醒
Rest, Jon Snow. We need you sharp tomorrow.
现在 你已经见过你的对手
So you've met the enemy,
也拟定了战术
drawn up your battle plans.
是啊 但愿能管用
Aye, for what they're worth.
你对他的了解仅凭一面之缘
You've known him for the space of a single conversation,
你和你亲信的顾问们
you and your trusted advisors,
就凑在一块儿 制定计划
and you sit around making your plans
对付这个你们并不知根知底的人
on how to defeat a man you don't know.
我与他一起生活过
I lived with him.
我了解他的思维方式
I know the way his mind works.
我知道他多么喜欢伤害别人
I know how he likes to hurt people.
你有没有想过 我或许对此有些见解？
Did it ever once occur to you that I might have some insight?
你说的对
You're right.
你以为他会落入你的陷阱
You think he's going to fall into your trap.
不会的 他才是那个设下陷进的人
He won't. He's the one who lays traps.
- 他太过自负 - 他喜欢玩游戏
- He's overconfident. - He plays with people.
他在这方面比你强很多 他这辈子都在玩弄别人
He's far better at it than you. He's been doing it all his life.
是啊 我这辈子都在干什么？耍扫帚吗？
Aye, and what have I been doing all my life? Playing with broomsticks?
我在塞外交手的敌人比拉姆斯·波顿更可怕
I fought beyond the Wall against worse than Ramsay Bolton.
我打败过比拉姆斯·波顿更恐怖的对手 守卫了长城
I've defended the Wall from worse than Ramsay Bolton.
你不了解他
You don't know him.
那好 告诉我
All right, tell me.
我们该怎么做？我们要怎么救回瑞肯？
What should we do? How do we get Rickon back?
我们救不回他
We'll never get him back.
瑞肯是奈德·史塔克的嫡子
Rickon is Ned Stark's trueborn son,
这使他对拉姆斯造成的威胁
which makes him a greater threat to Ramsay
比你这个私生子和我这个女儿大得多
than you, a bastard, or me, a girl.
只要他还活着 拉姆斯对临冬城的权利就充满争议
As long as he lives, Ramsay's claim to Winterfell will be contested,
这就意味着 他活不长
which means he won't live long.
我们不能放弃我们的弟弟
We can't give up on our brother.
听我说 拜托 他就是想让你犯错
Listen to me, please. He wants you to make a mistake.
他当然想 但我又能怎么做呢？
Of course he does. What should I do differently?
我不知道！我对战争一无所知
I don't know! I don't know anything about battles.
只是不要正中他的下怀
Just don't do what he wants you to do.
是啊 这是个好建议
Aye, that's good advice.
你觉得这很无聊吗？
You think that's obvious?
对 这是有一点无聊
Well, it is a bit obvious.
如果你早点问我的建议
If you had asked for my advice earlier,
我会告诉你不要攻打临冬城
I would have told you not to attack Winterfell
直到我们兵力更强 这是不是也很无聊？
until we had a larger force, or is that obvious, too?
我们何时兵力才能更强？！
When will we have a larger force?!
我们向所有可能支持我们的家族求过援了
We've pleaded with every house that'll have us.
黑鱼没法帮助我们
The Blackfish can't help us.
我们有这么多人已经很幸运了
We're lucky to have this many men.
- 这还不够！ - 是 是不够 但这是我们的全部了！
- It's not enough! - No, it's not enough. It's what we have!
有许多战斗在更恶劣的条件下赢过
Battles have been won against greater odds.
如果拉姆斯赢了
If Ramsay wins,
我不要活着回去
I'm not going back there alive.
你懂我的意思吗？
Do you understand me?
我永远不会再让他碰你
I won't let ever let him touch you again.
我会保护你 我保证
I'll protect you, I promise.
没人能保护我
No one can protect me.
人不能靠别人保护
No one can protect anyone.
你觉得还有希望？
You think there's hope?
我还从没看过这些波顿混蛋们打仗
I've never seen these Bolton fuckers fight.
他们也从没看过自由民打仗
And they've never seen the free folk fight,
所以 是的 还有希望
so, yes, there's hope.
你想替你的国王复仇 不是吗？
You want to avenge your king, don't you?
打败史坦尼斯的不是波顿
It wasn't the Boltons defeated Stannis.
是史坦尼斯自己
It was Stannis himself.
我很敬爱他
I loved the man.
他提拔了我 让我身居高位
He lifted me up and made me something.
但总有恶魔在他脑海中恶毒地低语
But he had demons in his skull whispering foul things.
- 你见到这些恶魔了？ - 什么？
- You saw these demons? - What?
不 这只是一种表达方式
No, it's a manner of speaking.
并不是……实际存在的恶魔
Not... actual demons.
好吧 你喜欢混球史坦尼斯
Well, you loved that cunt Stannis
我则喜欢被他烧死的那个人
and I loved the man he burned.
曼斯的脑海里没有什么恶魔
Mance didn't have demons in his skull.
他从不烧人 也不听信什么红女巫
He didn't torch people or listen to some red witch.
我信赖他
I believed in him.
我以为他会是那个带领我们度过长夜的人
I thought he was the man to lead us through the Long Night.
但我也错了 和你一样
But I was wrong just like you.
也许说到底是我们的错 就不该相信什么国王
Maybe that was our mistake, believing in kings.
琼恩·雪诺不是国王
Jon Snow's not a king.
对 他不是
No, he's not.
开战前夜 我得痛饮一番才睡得着
I need a good drink to help me sleep the night before a fight.
你要喝点吗？
You want some?
我有一罐酸羊奶
I have a jug of sour goat's milk
比你们这些南方娘炮的葡萄汁
stronger than any of that grape water
强到不知哪里去了
you southern twats like sucking on.
不用了 谢谢 听起来挺好喝的
No, thanks. It does sound delicious,
但我还是保持头脑清醒的好
but I better keep a clear head.
开战前夜我从来睡不着觉
I can never sleep the night before a battle.
那你一整晚都干些啥？
So what do you do all night?
到处走走
I walk.
边走边想
Think and walk.
边走边想 直到离营地够远
Think and walk until I'm far enough away from camp
没人能听到我裤裆里失禁的声音
that no one can hear me shitting my guts out.
拉得愉快
Happy shitting.
梅丽珊卓
女士
My lady.
您没参加战前会议
You weren't at the war council.
我不是战士
I'm not a soldier.
那您有什么建议吗？
Any advice?
别输掉
Don't lose.
如果我输掉 如果我死了……
If I do, if I fall...
别再复活我了
don't bring me back.
我必须去试
I'll have to try.
我命令你别再复活我了
I'm ordering you not to bring me back.
我不是你的仆人 琼恩·雪诺
I am not your servant, Jon Snow.
你在我的营地里 我是指挥官
You're in my camp. I'm the commander.
我侍奉光之王
I serve the Lord of Light.
我执行他的命令
I do what he commands.
您怎么知道他的命令？
How do you know what he commands?
我揭示他带来的预兆……
I interpret his signs...
尽我所能
as well as I can.
如果光之王不想让我复活你
If the Lord didn't want me to bring you back,
我又怎能做到呢？
how did I bring you back?
我没有超能力
I have no power.
我只有他赐予我的 而他把你赐予了我
Only what he gives me and he gave me you.
为什么？
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许你只在他的计划里扮演一个小角色 之后就没用了
Maybe you're only needed for this small part of his plan and nothing else.
也许他复活你只是为了让你再死一次
Maybe he brought you here to die again.
什么样的神会做出这种事来？
What kind of god would do something like that?
我们拥有的这个神
The one we've got.
上次我们见面还是在临冬城 对吧？
Last time we saw each other was at Winterfell, yes?
如果我的记忆没错 你好像拿我的身高开过玩笑
You were making jokes about my height, I seem to recall.
席恩·葛雷乔伊
每一个拿侏儒的身高开玩笑的人
Everyone who makes a joke about a dwarf's height
都以为自己是唯一一个开这种玩笑的
thinks he's the only person ever to make a joke about a dwarf's height.
“贵族的高度”“你这样的高度”
"The height of nobility," "a man of your stature,"
“让人仰望的高度”
"someone to look up to."
亚拉·葛雷乔伊
你们讲的笑话无外乎这么五六个
You're all making the same five or six jokes.
- 那是很久以前的事了 - 没错
- It was a long time ago. - It was.
从那以后你过得又怎样呢？
And how have things been going for you since then?
我看不太顺吧
Not so well, I gather.
难以想象你要是顺风顺水 还会谋杀史塔克家的孩子们
Can't imagine you would have murdered the Stark boys if things had been going well.
我没杀史塔克家的孩子
I didn't murder the Stark boys.
虽然我做过同样恶劣的事 甚至更糟
But I did things that were just as bad or worse.
他也为此付出了代价
And he paid for them.
看起来可没有
Doesn't seem like it.
他好像还活着呢
He's still alive.
我敢肯定这对你来说一定很复杂
It was complicated for you, I'm sure,
在临冬城长大
growing up at Winterfell.
从来都不太清楚自己究竟是谁
Never quite knowing who you were.
不过呢 我们每个人的生活都很复杂 不是吗？
But then, we all live complicated lives, don't we?
你们为我们带来了铁舰队的一百艘船
You've brought us 100 ships from the Iron Fleet
以及驾驶它们的船员
with men to sail them.
作为回报 我想你们希望我
In return, I expect you want me to support
支持你对铁群岛王位的要求？
your claim to the throne of the Iron Islands?
不是我的 是她的
Not my claim. Hers.
你有什么问题？
And what's wrong with you?
我不适合统治
I'm not fit to rule.
至少我们在这点上可以达成共识
We can agree upon that at least.
铁群岛有过女王吗？
Has the Iron Islands ever had a queen before?
跟维斯特洛一样
No more than Westeros.
我们的叔叔攸伦在失踪许久后回了家
Our Uncle Euron returned home after a long absence.
他谋杀了我们的父亲 抢走了属于亚拉的海盐王座
He murdered our father and took the Salt Throne from Yara.
如果我们留下 也会被他杀掉
He would have murdered us if we'd stayed.
提利昂大人告诉我 你们的父亲是个差劲的国王
Lord Tyrion tells me your father was a terrible king.
您和我在父亲这点上也一样
You and I have that in common.
没错
We do.
我们的父亲也都死于篡夺者之手
And both murdered by a usurper as well.
他们的船足够载我们的人吗？
Will their ships be enough?
加上之前伟主们的舰队 或许吧
With the former Masters' fleet, possibly.
勉强凑合
Barely.
铁舰队不止一百艘船
There are more than 100 ships in the Iron Fleet.
是的 而攸伦还在建造更多船
There are and Euron is building more.
他打算把这些船都献给您
He's going to offer them to you.
那我为什么不等他来呢？
So why shouldn't I wait for him?
他带来的不止铁舰队
The Iron Fleet isn't all he's bringing.
他还要……
He also wants to give you...
要你接受他那根巨大的话儿 我记得他说过
His big cock, I think he said.
您瞧 攸伦的礼物同时也是一份婚约
Euron's offer is also an offer of marriage, you see.
如果您不接受 也就得不到船
You won't get one without the other.
那我想你们的礼物是不含联姻要求的喽？
And I imagine your offer is free of any marriage demands?
我从不提要求 但任何事情我都乐意尝试 真的
I never demand, but I'm up for anything, really.
他杀了我们的父亲 也会杀了我们
He murdered our father and would have murdered us.
一旦他得到想要的 也立马会杀了您
He'll murder you as soon as you have what he wants.
他想要七大王国
The Seven Kingdoms.
整个七国
All of them.
而你们不想要七国？
And you don't want the Seven Kingdoms?
您的祖先击败了我们的祖先 夺走了铁群岛
Your ancestors defeated ours and took the Iron Islands.
我们请求你还回来
We ask you to give them back.
就这些？
And that's all?
我们还希望您能帮我们杀掉一两个
We'd like you to help us murder an uncle or two
觉得女人不适合统治的叔叔
who don't think a woman's fit to rule.
合情合理
Reasonable.
要是所有人都来要求独立怎么办？
What if everyone starts demanding their independence?
她不是要求 而是请求
She's not demanding, she's asking.
其他人也可以这样请求
The others are free to ask as well.
我们几个人的父亲都不是什么好人
Our fathers were evil men, all of us here.
他们留给我们一个被他们搞得一团糟的世界
They left the world worse than they found it.
我们不能像他们一样
We're not going to do that.
我们要留下一个更好的世界
We're going to leave the world better than we found it.
你将助我登上七国女王之位
You will support my claim as queen of the Seven Kingdoms
维护七国的统一
and respect the integrity of the Seven Kingdoms.
不再烧杀劫掠 奸淫无道
No more reaving, roving, raiding, or raping.
这是我们的生存方式
That's our way of life.
不再是了
No more.
"旺旺"
温旺·威格·温旺·铎迩·温旺
巨人
小琼恩·安柏
最后壁炉城伯爵
瑞肯·史塔克
史塔克家族的幼子
你喜欢游戏么 小家伙？
Do you like games, little man?
我们来玩个游戏
Let's play a game.
跑向你哥哥
Run to your brother.
你越早到他那
The sooner you make it to him,
就能越早跟他重逢
the sooner you get to see him again.
就这样
That's it.
游戏就这么玩
That's the game.
很容易的
Easy.
预备？
Ready?
跑
Go.
不 你得跑 记得么？
No, you have to run, remember?
这是游戏规则
Those are the rules.
不要啊
Don't.
准备冲锋
Prepare to charge.
准备冲锋！
Prepare to charge!
－拉弓！－拉弓！
- Draw! - Draw!
拉弓！
Draw!
放箭！
Loose!
冲！冲啊！跟着指挥官！
Go! Go! Follow your commander!
冲锋！战斗！
Run and fight!
搭箭！
Nock!
－拉弓！－拉弓！
- Draw! - Draw!
－放箭！－放箭！
- Loose! - Loose!
就是现在
Now.
骑兵 冲锋！
Cavalry, charge!
－搭箭！－搭箭！
- Nock! - Nock!
－拉弓！－拉弓！
- Draw! - Draw!
会伤了自己人的 放下
We'll just kill our own men. Stand down.
－放箭！－放箭！
- Loose! - Loose!
传令
Get word...
不！
No!
放箭！
Loose!
－放箭！－放箭！
- Loose! - Loose!
我们留在这也是等着挨操
We may as well be taking shits back here.
跟上！
Follow!
是时候了 去吧
It's time, go.
－北境属于谁？－我们！
- Who owns the North? - We do!
那就跟我上！
Show me!
嘿！
Hey!
步兵准备 前进！
Infantry, advance!
跟我上 小伙子们！打破他们的封锁！
With me, lads! Break their line!
救我！
Help me!
－托蒙德！－把他拉回来！
- Tormund! - Get him back!
步兵 推进！
Infantry, advance.
被包围了！
Both sides!
后退！
Fall back!
去他妈的 来吧！
Fuck this, come on!
我们要回家了！
We're going home!
（艾林家族）
培提尔·贝里席
小指头
打开城门！
Open the gate!
弓箭手去城墙上
Archers to the wall.
－他们全军覆没－是我们全军覆没
- Their army's gone. - Our army's gone.
我们有临冬城
We have Winterfell.
他们没有围城的人 我们只需要等
They don't have the men for a siege. All we have to do is wait.
弓箭手！
Archers!
去城墙上！
To the wall!
你之前建议一对一决斗 是吧？
You suggested one-on-one combat, didn't you?
我重新想了想
I've reconsidered.
我觉得这是个绝妙的主意
I think that sounds like a wonderful idea.
把我弟弟埋进地下墓窖
We're going to bury my brother in the crypt
挨着我父亲
next to my father.
琼恩
Jon.
他在哪？
Where is he?
珊莎
Sansa.
你好啊 珊莎
Hello, Sansa.
这就是我要呆的地方么？
Is this where I'll be staying now?
不是
No.
我们在一起的时间就要到头了
Our time together is about to come to an end.
没关系
That's all right.
你不能杀我
You can't kill me.
我现在是你的一部分
I'm part of you now.
你的言语会消失
Your words will disappear.
你的家族会消失
Your house will disappear.
你的姓氏会消失
Your name will disappear.
关于你的一切将永远消失
All memory of you will disappear.
我的猎犬绝对不会伤害我
My hounds will never harm me.
你已经七天没有喂过它们了
You haven't fed them in seven days.
你自己说的
You said it yourself.
它们是忠犬
They're loyal beasts.
的确
They were.
但现在它们饿疯了
Now they're starving.
给我
Sit.
坐下
Down.
下去！
Down!
下去！下去！
Down! Down!
下去！
Down!
衣柜字幕组出品
本集关键字：亚赞·佐·夸格兹
剧情没看懂？ 典故不清楚？
维基新站网址：http://asoiaf.huiji.wiki/